Amit Kumar Upadhyay

I love to play with languages & try to learn new things every day. I'm good in Python, C, Java, C++, and JavaScript. I am very much interested in Data Structure & Algorithms and love to study them. I have decent experience in software development too. I love building things, making them scalable. I have made some software products which are present in the market. To know more about me and my projects please visit http://binomial.me

amitupadhyayemail@gmail.com

7769942159

e binomial.me

github.com/amit-upadhyay-IT

a goo.gl/TgWjXw

WORK EXPERIENCE / INTERNSHIPS

Edelweiss Financial (Intern) Node.js developer, Researcher

06/2017 - 08/2017 Achievements/Tasks Mumbai

 Developed an optimized CRM system and moved dependency of CRM to open source platforms. And Increased the performance to 33x (33 times faster)

Afferent Technology Pvt. Ltd. (Intern) Android Developer

07/2016 - 08/2016

Pune

Achievements/Tasks

 Worked on developing Android Application for their IOT product.

Freelancing Work Android Application - ClickIn

08/2016 - 09/2016

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.amitupadhyay.clickin

Achievements/Tasks

 Designed & Developed android app which is being used by their customers

MY PRODUCTS ON PLAYSTORE

Touch Me | Color Shades (Game) (12/2016 – Present)

- An interesting game which is based on your reflexes (how fast do you react?), hand-eye coordination and visual stimulus.
- The game is completely designed and developed by me.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.amitupadhyay.touchme

Kisan Kalyan | Farmer Welfare (03/2017 – 04/2017)

- The concept of this app is to provide all services related to farming under one roof.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=krishikalyan.aupadhyay.myapp

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering(B.E)

Army Institute of Technology

07/2014 - Present

7.46 CGPA

Branch

Information Technology

SKILLS

Node.js

Android

Firebase

Redis

MongoDB

Data Structures and Algorithms

OOP

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

1. Crypt-git (Make GitHub private) (09/2017 – Present)

a command line utility written in node.js which enables to work privately on your GitHub repo for Free. -> https://github.com/amit-upadhyay-IT/crypt-git

2. GetCountryCode (12/2016 - Present)

A library to get telephone country code in Android. Provides you API to work smoothly in your development.

3. GetLocationFast (04/2017 – 07/2017)

The fastest ever "displaying users current address" library available here -> github.com/amit-upadhyay-IT/GetLocationFast

4. Contacts search (05/2017 – 05/2017)

An Android library which fetches the contacts from mobile and allows to search for it. Link- https://github.com/amit-upadhyay-IT/contacts-searchandroid

5. StackOverflow Contributions

Made contributions to the community in Firebase (Top 5% badge), Android (Top 10% badge) and Java (Top 20% badge) -> www.stackoverflow.com/users/5411888/amit-upadhyay

6. Binomial.me (Technical Blog)

So this is Binomial an awesome platform to deliver tutoring services on, that one would actually love to use. Link: http://binomial.me

HACKATHON PROJECTS

Infosys Hackathon - 1st rank (09/2016 – 09/2016)

Secured 1st position, among 40 teams from different colleges.

Techgig Code Gladiators, By Jio (04/2017 – 06/2017)

Developed an completely secure offline transaction application. Secured 3rd rank among 8000 participants all over India.

Smart India Hackathon (03/2017 – 04/2017)

Developed an app for prediction of rainfall. Also qualified for final round

PROJECTS...

Smart Pay (08/2017 - 11/2017)

An app capable of doing transactions in offline mode securely. Enabling merchants to offer alternate payment solutions to their customers to drive cashless transactions.

Online Study Portal

This application is written in Node.js using MEAN stack framework, excluding AngularJS. It was my mini project in my 5th semester. This is kinda knowlegde sharing portal where one can share posts. http://ourdbmspro.herokuapp.com/

EDUCATION

XII (Senior Secondary), Science CBSE Board (Kendriya Vidyalaya O.F Dum Dum, Kolkata)

04/2013 - 03/2014

84%

X (Secondary) [2012]

CBSE Board (Kendriya Vidyalaya O.F Dum Dum, Kolkata)

04/2011 - 03/2012

9.4 CGPA

PROJECTS...

Code Well (08/2017 - Present)

A beautiful and optimized android app in terms of size, user experience and design. This app contains in-depth solutions to problems based on different Data Structures and Algorithms.

draw-with-me (12/2017 - 12/2017)

Node.js socket based application for white board sharing, made using the socket.io library. Link- https://github.com/amit-upadhyay-IT/draw-with-me

CRM system

Developed an optimized CRM system, using Node.js, Redis DB, Lua and .. more at Edelweiss. Moved to dependency of previous CRM to open source platforms. Also increased the performance about 33x.

Parking App (10/2016 – 10/2016)

Developed an efficient solution for managing the parking lots for Infosys in hinjewadi, Pune. The software product involved Android app, IOT for doing some OCR and securely updating them on common server.

Techfest Event application

This application was used by participants of an event in our college Techfest. It was primarily developed for giving a Quiz which was screening for the event. Also it gives updates to the contestants. Linkhttps://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.amitupadhyay.ait.approach

Touch Me(Game)

An interesting Game which is based on your reflexes (how fast do you react?), hand-eye coordination and visual stimulus. The game is designed and developed by me. Link- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.amitupadhyay.touchme

Binomial

A Blog that provides in depth programming and technologies knowledge, know more about it here-http://binomial.me/about/

LANGUAGES









JavaScript

CERTIFICATIONS

CodeChef Certified Data Structure & Algorithms Programme (03/2018 – Present)

link- http://binomial.me/me/myccdsap.pdf

ANDROID DEVELOPER (07/2016 – Present)

link-

https://www.edureka.co/lms/certificate/f63a34aaaa5d145872d826fad7 609e7d

FUTURE PLANS

Contribute to make our country a more better place to

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

Basketball

Table Tennis

Deep Learning

Blockchain